<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tracing bytes</title>
    <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tracing bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.127.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kraashen.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simple LAN party network with Zyxel GS1900-24E managed switch</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-03-30-simple-lan-party-network-with-zyxel-gs1900-24e-managed-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-03-30-simple-lan-party-network-with-zyxel-gs1900-24e-managed-switch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We were about to have a LAN party during easter. Network setup was really simple: one consumer-grade 10/100/1000 router with a connection to the Internet with a NATted network, one port for the host of the party, and extending this network from another interface behind a switch for everyone else. Originally we had only 10/100 capable switch, but as the location we were in had now also support for faster uplink, we needed to upgrade the switch to get everything out of the bandwidth available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering With Radare - Binary internals</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-03-11-reverse-engineering-basics-with-radare-binary-internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-03-11-reverse-engineering-basics-with-radare-binary-internals/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, basics and fundamentals for reverse engineering software were discussed. This time I thought about writing a bit more about getting a bit further in inspecting and understanding software binaries. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at one password guess reverse engineering challenge using Radare.
Goals The goal is to reverse engineer a simple binary and understanding of the flow of disassembled code, how to read it, and understand how it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering With Radare - Fundamentals and Basics</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-01-22-reverse-engineering-basics-with-radare-fundamentals-and-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2018-01-22-reverse-engineering-basics-with-radare-fundamentals-and-basics/</guid>
      <description>As I got more and more curious on how software works, I felt it essential as a software and systems engineer to start understanding deeper low-level internals of software. So I thought about diving more into the topic of reverse engineering from software developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective using an open source tool called Radare. There are plenty of extremely well written Radare tutorials on reverse engineering which may include topics such as finding hidden passwords and injection techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Web Server Using Caddy and Github Webhooks</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-28-raspberry-pi-web-server-using-caddy-with-git-webhooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 16:57:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-28-raspberry-pi-web-server-using-caddy-with-git-webhooks/</guid>
      <description>After setting up the DMZ in my home network, it was time to get hands on with the actual server. I heard of a web server called Caddy, which is a HTTP/2 HTTPS-by-default web server written in Go. I got into Go as a programming language some time ago recently and I was a bit excited about a possibility of running a production capable web server with it on a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik 493G with a Home DMZ</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-22-mikrotik-493g-with-a-home-dmz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 02:37:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-22-mikrotik-493g-with-a-home-dmz/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I showed one way to set up a home network using Mikrotik Routerboard. Next up in my project list was to set up a Raspberry Pi web server to host my own website and a blog (this one in fact). This required some tweaks to my home network set up as I needed to allow access to a device in my network from the public Internet. As Mikrotik allows nice configurability to do this kind of set ups, I dove into some of Mikrotik&amp;rsquo;s own manuals to start up with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up MikroTik 493G as a home router (&#43;WLAN AP)</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-15-setting-up-mikrotik-493g-as-a-home-router-wlan-ap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 23:39:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2017-10-15-setting-up-mikrotik-493g-as-a-home-router-wlan-ap/</guid>
      <description>MikroTik is a company that sells e.g. configurable network appliances for a decent price point. I thought that their routerboard could be great for both casual and home lab use, so I went and bought a second-hand routerboard to tinker with. It felt it would be a nice change and an addition to get hands-on and acquainted with setting up computer networks from the scratch besides looking at tcpdumps/whatnot
Routerboards have an operating system called RouterOS, which is developed by MikroTik and is based on Linux kernel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Component analysis of popular free Android software</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2015-04-23-component-analysis-of-popular-free-android-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 18:23:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2015-04-23-component-analysis-of-popular-free-android-software/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I took a look at some of the Privacytools.io guide&amp;rsquo;s Android applications and their respective OpenSSL versions due to an inspiration that a study gave me [1]. I also thought to continue this as a follow-up and take a look into some of the popular free Android software available on Google Play and tried to study what they are built upon.
Study set up Choose target Android applications based on common popularity among people and Play Store lists of popular free applications Collect the Android Application Packages (APK) from the Google Play Store Applications were downloaded on 2015-04-15 Use BOMTotal[2] service for scanning the application components Collect the Bill of Materials URLs, tool version identification, and software components including their respective versions Focus was on OpenSSL and getting familiar with 3rd party ad components Collect OpenSSL version history from the OpenSSL release notes and use the release intervals for &amp;lsquo;best before dates&amp;rsquo; mentioned in the original study on Privacytools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow-up: Android privacy tools best served fresh</title>
      <link>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2015-04-14-follow-up-android-privacy-tools-best-served-fresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 05:49:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kraashen.github.io/posts/2015-04-14-follow-up-android-privacy-tools-best-served-fresh/</guid>
      <description>Recently, there was a study published on OpenSSL versions used by privacy conscious software recommended in the Privacytools.io guide [1]. This study took a stance on not only the OpenSSL crypto library, but the components used by software critical to privacy and safety. The study revealed that many applications are using outdated components. As mobile world is becoming a significant part of how we communicate with people and mobile malware development in Q1 2014 continues to focus exclusively on the Android platform [2], this follow-up study focuses on Android applications mentioned in the study.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
